

Vijayan Kuniyil Financial Controller

Tel: +9715 07729658 +918589056246

e mail: vijayamk@gmail.com, Abu Dhabi, UAE

Objective

Seeking to continue my career in the Hospitality Management and deploying my years of experience and knowledge for the best interest of my employer and the business stakeholders.

Professional Summary

Focused Finance management professional with a proven track record earned through an industry career spanning 25 years of working for some of the most prominent hospitality organizations in U. A E.

Dedicated and enthusiastic Financial Controller for large hotel and catering management companies in UAE and assisted in preopening and mobilization of hotels and large number of catering operations in reputed companies.

Skills

- Revenue Management
- Cost Control
- Financial Reporting
- Preopening of Hotels
- Mobilization of Catering
- Preparation of Budget
- Team Player
- Positive and upbeat
- **❖** Goal-oriented
- Strong communication skills
- Leadership skills
- Consumer Behavior

Strength

> 22 Years' Experience as Financial Controller in the field of Hospitality Accounting. (Hotels, Catering & corporate office of hospitality firm in U.A.E) & 5 Years as Accountant in Hospitality Field

Professional Experience

1. Finance Manager - Abu Dhabi Country Club

Abu Dhabi Country Club owned by Abu Dhabi Sports Council From 20 Dec 2018 – 20 Nov 2020

2. Cluster Financial Controller

Al Marfa Pearl Hotels Management LLC, Abu Dhabi

Financial Controller for three Hotels (Maisan Hotel Dubai, Mirfa Hotel & Liwa Hotel Abu Dhabi) .Did the Preopening of Maisan Hotel (256 Rooms) in D I P Dubai under the same Management From February 2014 till 15 Dec 2018.

3. Financial Controller

National Corporation for Tourism & Hotels (NCT&H) 4 years June 2009 - December 2013

Financial Controller in corporate office for the Catering & Support Service Division Green Mubazaraah Chalets (200 Deluxe Chalets complex in Al Ain) Al Ain Rest Houses (190 rooms)

4. Financial Controller

Nojoum Hospitality – Dubai (Hospitality Division of Al Ghurair Group)

1 year August 2008 - June 2009

Financial Controller from the preopening period . Deluxe Hotel apartment with (160 Rooms) & F & B outlets- Did the Pre Opening of this Property.

5. Financial Controller

National Corporation for Tourism & Hotels (NCT&H) 4 years March 2004 – July 2008

F.C in corporate office for the Catering & Support Service Division of NCT&H, Green Mubazaraah Chalets (200 Deluxe Chalets complex in Al Ain)& Al Ain Rest Houses (190 rooms)

6. Financial Controller

Mafraq Hotel Abu Dhabi - 4 star deluxe hotel ,managed by National Corporation for Tourism & Hotels (NCT&H) 6 years November 1998 - March 2004

Work Handle on the above assignments

- ➤ Providing Strategic Financial Leadership and support to the property and its constituents' units.
- Overseeing and directing the day to day financial operation of the division.
- ➤ Budgeting, forecasting and analysing the financial data to support key financial decisions.
- > Cost analysis of existing operations and for potential new facilities
- Monitoring and reporting of financial obligations and Reviews and recommendations for efficiency improvements
- > Finalisation of accounts on monthly basis.
- > Comparison of statement of affairs with the budget and forecast.
- > Preparation of yearly budget, revenue projection, forecast etc
- To ensure efficient systems are in place to accurately record revenue and expenditure information that need to present on a regular basis.
- Liaison with vendors, bankers, investors and insurance bodies for better relationship.
- ➤ Reliever to the General Manager during his vacations and absence.

Special Task on above assignments

- ➤ Did the preopening of Maisan Hotel in Dubai Investment Park from 2017 under the management of Al Marfa Pearl Hotels Management.
- ➤ Did the pre opening of Nojoum Al Dar Hotel Apartments 160 Rooms Deluxe Apartments with F & B Outlets in Dubai.
- Did the pre opening of Green Mubazaraah Chalets Al Ain, a 200 Chalets Complex in Al Ain.
- ➤ Mobilization of lot of Catering & support service centres in NCT&H
- ➤ Did the ERP Solution Set up Oracle Net Suite –Set up in Abu Dhabi Country Club

Computer Knowledge

- > Experienced in Opera
- > FBM Hotel package
- Micros Point of Sale
- Oracle Net Suite ERP
- > SAGE ACCPAC Financial Package
- Paytrax Payroll package
- MS Office.

Educational Qualification

M.Com Studied and passed from Department of Management Studies –

from the Campus of University of Calicut, Kerala, India - 1991

Specialisation in Financial Management

B.Com Passed with class from University of Calicut, kerala, India - 1988

Specialisation in Advanced Accounting, Cost Accounting and

Business Statistics

Seminars & Trainings Attended

1. I F R S (International Financial Reporting Standards) conducted by Ernst & Young and Emile Woolf International, Dubai 2009.

- 2. I F R S (International Financial Reporting Standards) conducted by Ernst & Young and Emile Woolf International, Abu Dhabi 2009.
- 3. I F R S (International Financial Reporting Standards) conducted by Ernst & Young and Emile Woolf International, Dubai 2007.
- 4. I A S (International Accounting Standards) Updates conducted by Ernst & Young , Abu Dhabi 2005

References

Mr. V. M Abraham

Director of Finance

GHQ- Officers Club Abu Dhabi

Tel: 050- 5743414

Abraham58sunny@gmail.com

Mr. Salim Touma

General Manager

Al Marfa Pearl Hotels Management, Abu Dhabi

Salim.touma@maisanhotel.ae

Mr. Shyam Saroff

Internal Audit Manager

National Corporation for Tourism & Hotels

ssaraf@ncth.ae

Tel: 050 4410660

Other Personal Information

Nationality Indian

Contact Number +97150- 7729658

+97152 - 6949720

E Mail vijayamk@gmail.com

Fax 02-4466395

Contact Address P.O. Box: 47776

Abu Dhabi

Known Languages English, Hindi, Arabic (moderate), Malayalam

Date of Birth 21 April 1965

Married Sex Male

Status of Visa Residence

Driving License UAE Driving License